247spares.co.uk 2019-06-22

# 247 Spares - Buy Cheap Car Parts Online! - UK

This website uses cookies. By continuing to use this website you are giving consent to cookies being used, also agree to site Terms and Privacy    ACCEPT COOKIES ")

247spares allows users to source automative parts using its online portal. We operate in "real time" and use Google Cloud Servers. We are Cloud based. 

247 Spares, 247 Spares Network, www.247spares.co.uk, and www.247spares.com are all trading names of Citynet Datacom Ltd. 

###  What information do we collect about you? 

(If a Consumer) 247spares collects your name, contact details, and Vehicle Registration Mark. 

(If a Dealer) 247 spares collects the details submitted by the Dealer on the Dealer Application Form. 

###  How do we obtain your information? 

You will have provided us with information directly because you want to obtain a quotation for a spare part (or to buy a spare part) and for us to put you in touch with potential suppliers. 

A Dealer will have provided us with information directly because they want to be able to potentially source and provide parts to potential buyers. 

###  Why do we need to collect and store your information? 

This will enable us to perform our contractual duties to you. It means that we can put you in touch with subscribed members for you to obtain the parts that you require. 

This will enable us to perform our contractual duties to you. It means that we can put you in touch with potential buyers for you to provide them with the parts that they require. 

###  Will we share your information with anyone else? 

Our website which runs the online portal will pass your personal data on to a selection of our subscribed members to help you to find the part you need. The number of subscribed members who receive your information will depend upon what parts you require. 

The same applies for Dealers who will be put in touch with the customers seeking quotations for spare parts. 

Any third parties that we may share your data with are obliged to keep your details securely and to use them only to fulfill the service that you require of them. We require our subscribed members to confirm that they will adhere to the same terms as we do in respect of your data. Our subscribed members will also be bound by the same data protection laws and requirements that we are. 

###  How will we use your information? 

247Spares will process (collect, store and use) the information that you provide in a manner compatible with the EU's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We will endeavor to keep your information accurate and up to date, and we will not keep it for longer than is necessary. 

###  How long will we keep your information and will it be secure? 

We take security seriously and all of your information will be stored on our encrypted systems. We are a Cloud based business and use Google Services, but your data is all UK based and located in the UK, so the same rules that we will uphold to keep your data safe will apply to them. 

We won't hold the data that you submit to us to obtain a quotation for longer than necessary to enable us to keep up with our legal and regulatory requirements. 

###  Your rights 

· You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal information that we hold. 

· You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. 

· You have the right to request that your personal information be erased in certain circumstances. 

· You also have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your information in some circumstances. 

· You have the right to object to us processing your information. 

· You also have the right to request that we transfer your information to another organisation. 

We want to make sure that your personal details are accurate and up to date. 247spares at your request, can confirm what information we hold about you, how it is processed, and how long it is retained for. We may ask you to confirm your identity for the purposes of responding to your request. Please contact us using the details provided below. 

###  Other websites 

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy notice only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies/notices. 

###  Changes to our privacy notice 

We regularly review our privacy notice and any updates will be posted to this web page. This policy notice was last updated in June 2018. 

###  How to contact us 

Please contact us if you have any questions. Our Data Protection Officer is Imran Asghar. 

Citynet Datacom Ltd 

Tel: 0207 100 1939

###  Complaints 

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and we are registered with the ICO. 

If you are not happy with how we collect or process your information or just want some further information on your rights, you can contact us. You can also make a complaint to the ICO. Further information may be found at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/>
